broadbandgenie.co.uk 2018-09-25

# Privacy Policy - Broadband Genie

### _Updated May 2018_

## Overview 

  * The use of Broadband Genie is strictly subject to this privacy policy.

  * We may collect some personal information from you when you use the Broadband Genie website. The section entitled ‘The information we collect and how we collect it’ contains full details. 

  * The section entitled ‘How we use your information’ details the manner in which we use this information.

  * We will share your information with other companies when required to by law. 

  * You can ask us any questions about your personal information at any time by emailing [privacy@broadbandgenie.co.uk](mailto:privacy@broadbandgenie.co.uk)

## About us

Broadband Genie is owned and operated by Genie Ventures Ltd.

Our company registration number: 05085554

Our registered address is:

Carlyle House   
Carlyle Road   
Cambridge   
CB4 3DN

## The information we collect and how we collect it

When you use the Broadband Genie website we may collect personal information about you. This information is as follows:

  * Your postcode: If you perform a check for available broadband services in your area, or if you use our speed test

  * Your email address: If you choose to have a copy of your comparison results sent to your inbox, or if you apply for a reward or a special offer

  * Your email address or Twitter handle: If you are entering an on-site competition or survey. We may also collect your age, gender, postcode and location if relevant to a particular survey 

  * The details of your visit are tracked through the use of cookies. Please see our cookie policy for more information

The following sections explain why we collect this information, how we use it and who we share it with. 

## Why do we collect this information?

All companies are required to have a valid lawful basis in order to use (or process) personal data. 

The lawful basis under which we collect and use your personal information is as follows: it is necessary for the performance of a contract, or pre-contractual steps, if this information is collected in either of the following ways:

  * You apply for a reward or a special offer that Broadband Genie is providing as part of your broadband order with your chosen supplier

  *  You are entering an on-site competition or survey 

In any other circumstance, the legal basis under which we collect and use your personal information is that it is necessary for our legitimate business interests. "Legitimate interests" refers to the interests of our company in conducting and managing our business, in order to supply the best service and the most relevant user experience.

With any personal information that is collected for our legitimate interests, we have to consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative), and your rights under data protection laws. Our legitimate business interests cannot override your interests - we will not use your personal information for activities where our interests are overridden by any potential impact to you.

You have a right to object to the reasons we collect any of the information detailed within this privacy document. The section ‘Contact us or make a complaint’ at the end of this document explains how you can do this. 

## How we use your information

When you click through a product link on Broadband Genie to a third party website we will use cookies to track the progress of your visit through to your chosen broadband supplier’s site. This is to ensure we receive a commission once the supplier completes your order on its website. For more information on how Broadband Genie is funded, please follow this link.  

Other ways we may use your personal information: 

### To provide accurate postcode and speed test results

When you perform an availability or speed check on our website we will use your postcode to complete this check. This is essential to display the most accurate picture of which suppliers are available where you live, or your current broadband speed. 

Broadband Genie partners with SamKnows to perform this postcode check and broadbandspeedchecker.co.uk to provide speed test results. For more information on how we work with these companies, please refer to the ‘Who we share your information with’ section below. 

### To fulfil a competition prize, reward or special offer 

We will collect your email address if you apply for a reward or a special offer that Broadband Genie is providing as part of your broadband order with your chosen supplier. 

We need this information in order to send you your reward or special offer once your transaction has been completed through your chosen broadband supplier and your broadband has been installed. 

We keep this information for a maximum of 12 months; unless you explicitly opt in to receiving marketing emails from Broadband Genie, in which case your information will be kept until you unsubscribe from receiving further emails from us. 

We may also collect your email address or Twitter username if you enter a competition on Broadband Genie. We need this information in order to send you your prize once the competition has closed. We keep this information for a maximum of 12 months.

### To email you your comparison results 

If you ask us to email you your broadband comparison results, we will use your email address to send these to you. 

We will not keep your email address unless you explicitly opt in to receiving marketing emails from Broadband Genie, in which case your information will be kept until you unsubscribe from receiving further emails from us. 

### To provide a broadband comparison service over the phone 

We provide customer support telephone numbers across the Broadband Genie website in order to provide an additional method for users to complete their broadband purchase. 

We partner with Simplify Digital to provide this service. Broadband Genie does not collect any personal information via these phone numbers, but our partners may do. 

For more information on how we work with Simplify Digital, please refer to the ‘Who we share your information with’ section below. 

### To improve our user experience 

We use information about your visits to Broadband Genie in order to develop and improve our website experience for users. 

For further details on the information we collect for the purpose of improving user experience and how to opt out, please see our cookie policy.

## Who we share your information with 

### Simplify Digital

We partner with Simplify Digital provide an additional method for users to complete their broadband purchase by ordering over the phone. Broadband Genie does not collect any personal information via these phone numbers.

Simplify Digital may collect personal information including but not limited to name, email address, phone number, broadband supplier and product purchased. This information is used for internal sales reporting only and is kept for a maximum of three years. For more information, please see Simplify Digital’s [privacy policy](https://www.simplifydigital.co.uk/corporate/privacy-policy/). 

### Hotjar

We use a company called Hotjar in order to better understand our users’ needs and to optimise our service by studying and improving user experience (how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc) 

Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behaviour and their devices - in particular a device's IP address (captured and stored only in anonymised form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only) and preferred language.

Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymised user profile. Neither Hotjar nor Broadband Genie will ever use this information to identify individual users, or to match it with further data on an individual user. 

For further details, please see Hotjar’s privacy policy by clicking on [this link](https://www.hotjar.com/privacy). 

You can opt out of the creation of a user profile, Hotjar’s storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar’s use of tracking cookies on other websites by following this [opt-out link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out).

### SurveyGizmo

SurveyGizmo is a data collection platform. We use SurveyGizmo to host surveys for the purposes of gathering research for editorial content and visitor feedback to improve our site.

The data collected is encrypted and stored in SurveyGizmo's EU data centre. SurveyGizmo does not sell or share data collected by surveys, and does not have access to survey data except when specifically requested by us for the purposes of providing technical or customer support. 

This data is kept for a maximum of 12 months. 

For further information see SurveyGizmo’s [privacy policy](https://www.surveygizmo.eu/privacy/).

### Giftcloud

Giftcloud is our chosen voucher supplier for all incentive offers provided by Broadband Genie. We use Giftcloud because it allow us to offer a wide variety of rewards to our customers. 

We send Giftcloud the email addresses for all approved sales when running rewards or special offers. Giftcloud then send the reward to the customer. It does not use this data for anything else, or share it with any third party. 

Giftcloud holds your email address for a 12-month period to ensure we are able to answer any queries from our customers. 

For further information see Giftcloud’s [privacy policy](https://www.giftcloud.com/uk/privacy).

### Feefo 

Feefo is a review platform. We use Feefo to gather customer feedback in order to maintain and improve our current service. 

When a user consents to supplying us with their email address whilst using the website and subsequently purchases, Feefo may send an email to that user on behalf of Broadband Genie in order to obtain a review. 

Feefo receive a name, email address and information about the product the user purchases. This data is stored by Feefo in order to provide us with statistics for that user’s experience. 

Feefo does not use this information for any other purposes. Please refer to Feefo’s [privacy policy](https://www.feefo.com/business/gb_en/privacy-policy) for further information. 

### Broadbandspeedchecker.co.uk 

Our broadband speed test is powered by broadbandspeedchecker.co.uk. When you check your speed on Broadband Genie we will share your computer’s IP address with broadbandspeedchecker.co.uk in order to show you your current broadband speed. 

This IP address is anonymised and does not personally identify a user. Broadbandspeedchecker.co.uk may share IP data, along with speed tests and network measurements, with third parties to compile aggregate information about network statistics and usage in particular areas. Broadband Genie does not store this information anywhere. 

For more information, please see Broadbandspeedchecker.co.uk’s [privacy policy](https://www.broadbandspeedchecker.co.uk/privacy_policy.aspx). 

### SamKnows

Broadband Genie partners with SamKnows to perform postcode checks on our website in order to show users accurate available supplier and deal information at that exact location. 

In order to display these results Broadband Genie sends a user’s postcode to SamKnows, which then passes back its data to populate our comparison tables accurately. 

SamKnows keeps this information for seven days before deleting. Broadband Genie does not store this information anywhere. 

Please refer to SamKnows’ [privacy policy](https://samknows.com/legal/privacy-policy) for further information. 

## How we keep your information safe 

The security of our users’ data is of primary importance at Broadband Genie. We have in place several procedures to keep your information safe, which include but are not limited to:

  * Https protocols: We use https on Broadband Genie to encrypt user data between the device and our website.

  * Password protection: Our content-management systems are secured via passwords. We use LastPass to further secure our passwords within the company.

  * Google authentication: Our reporting, email, Google Drive, content-management systems, Analytics and AdWords are all secured via Google Authentication, which is backed up by two-step verification logins.

  * User passwords: Where users have access to Broadband Genie, we would implore them to consider choosing a secure password and to protect it.

  * Data deletion: We delete all non-essential data after a short, relevant period (outlined above). This includes an overwhelming majority of the personal data.

  * Access: Within our own company, access to personal data is limited to a small number of relevant individuals.

  * Firewalls and antivirus: We ensure staff are using devices with up-to-date firewalls and antivirus software.

## Changes to our privacy policy

Broadband Genie’s privacy policy may be subject to occasional change. Any changes to our privacy policy in the future will be posted to the website and, where appropriate, through email notification.

## Contact us or make a complaint

If you would like to find out what information we hold on you, change, correct, remove or request we stop using this information, or make a complaint, please email [privacy@broadbandgenie.co.uk](mailto:privacy@broadbandgenie.co.uk) or send a letter to:

Broadband Genie   
Carlyle House  
Carlyle Road   
Cambridge   
CB4 3DN

If you do wish to make a complaint, or are concerned about the way in which we are handling your data, you can raise this concern with a relevant regulatory authority within your country of residence. In the UK this is the [Information Commissioner’s Office](https://ico.org.uk/for-the-public/raising-concerns/).
